<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | CoMo-PH</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>© CoMo-PH 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoMo modelling tool for the Philippines</title>
      <link>/project/como-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/como-tools/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 International Modeling Consortium (CoMo)</title>
      <link>/project/policy-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/policy-analysis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 International Modelling Consortium (CoMo)</title>
      <link>/project/como/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/como/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 International Modelling Consortium (CoMo) in the Philippines</title>
      <link>/project/como-ph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/como-ph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;evolution-of-the-pandemic-in-the-philippines&#34;&gt;Evolution of the pandemic in the Philippines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 11th of January 2020, the Philippines 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.doh.gov.ph&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Department of Health&lt;/a&gt; issued its first advisory concerning persons who had travel history to Wuhan, China which at that time was the epicentre of the COVID-19 outbreak. The issuance of this advisory was triggered by the first death attributable to COVID-19 in China. On the 21st of January, the first patient-under-investigation (PUI) who happened to be a traveler from China was investigated and was pronounced as negative of COVID-19. One week after (Jan. 28), the DOH convened the Inter-agency Task Force on Emerging and Re-emerging Infections (IATF-EID). The nCOV-tracker (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ncovtracker.doh.gov.ph/),&#34;&gt;https://ncovtracker.doh.gov.ph/),&lt;/a&gt; which is a public dashboard that shows the number of PUM, PUI, and confirmed cases, was also launched on the same day. The DOH convened the first command conference on the next day with regional directors as participants. On Jan. 30, the first confirmed case of COVID-19, which was an imported case from Wuhan, China, was declared. This happened during the same day when the World Health Organization (WHO) had declared COVID-19 as a Public Health Emergency of International Concern. The next day, a travel ban to and from Hubei, China was promulgated by the Philippine government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 1st of Feb., the first mortality due to COVID-19, who was a close contact of the first imported case, was pronounced in the Philippines. On Feb 5, a 60-year-old female Chinese PUI tested positive and was declared as the 3rd case in the Philippines. This prompted the Epidemiology Bureau of the DOH, along with the Philippine National Police- Criminal Investigation and Detection Group (PNP-CIDG), to start tracing the contacts of the confirmed cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A month after (March 5), two more cases were confirmed in the country and were added in the roster. Having no travel history as confirmed by the Bureau of Immmigration, the 5th case was pronounced to be the first local case on March 7. This prompted the DOH to raise the COVID-19 ALERT System to Code Red sublevel 1. Mr. Rodrigo Duterte, the current president, made a nationwide declaration of a State of Public Health Emergency due to COVID-19. A day prior COVID-19 was declared as a pandemic by the WHO Director-General on March 11, the president issued a region-wide suspension of all classes in Metro Manila. On March 12, the IATF-EID and the DOH raised the COVID Alert System to Code Red sublevel 2 placing Metro Manila under General Community Quarantine as a means of curbing viral transmission. On March 16, the president declared a nationwide declaration of a State of Calamity and placed the entire Luzon Island on an Enhanced Community Quarantine (ECQ) until April 14. On April 6, Mr. Duterte pronounced in a night press conference that he is inclining towards ECQ extension until April 30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-covid-19-epidemic-models-in-the-philippines&#34;&gt;Current COVID-19 epidemic models in the Philippines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented below are some of the current models that are focused on Metro Manila (National Capital Region).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model/Proponents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status quo estimated peak size (include detected and undetected)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Status quo peak time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remarks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;SEIR Model/UPD ModApp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;250000 - 550000 as of 1 April 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;April 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;S0 = 1 million; R0 = 1.48; cumulative number of infected = 900000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;SIR provincial/city-level/UPLB Biomathematics Team&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;140000 - 320000 as of 4 April 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;April - June 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;R0 = 1.5 - 4 (R0 most likely at 1.5 - 2.5); Peak size is 25% of total infected&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;SIR Model/Darwin Bandoy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;250000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;End of June&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;S0 = 1 million; R0 = 2.5 (95% CI 1.1 = 2.5)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A web-based disease surveillance platform that uses deterministic compartmental modeling was developed by people from Ateneo Center for Computing Competency and Research (ACCCRe) of Ateneo de Manila University, University of the Philippines Manila - National Telehealth Center (UP-NTHC), and the Department of Health-Epidemiology Bureau developed. This was known as FASSSTER, or Feasibility Analysis of Syndromic Surveillance using Spatio-Temporal Epidemiological Modeler or FASSSTER. In modeling projections, this platform uses the following interventions: community quarantine, social distancing, and optimal testing on the total number of confirmed cases, deaths, and recoveries over time. Data generated from this platform are being used by the Inter-agency Task Force (IATF) in their recommendations and the government’s decision to extend the enhanced community quarantine (ECQ) until April 30. Presented below are the scenarios that have been modelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peak number of cases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peak dates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Do nothing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2000000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;May 30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ECQ implemented but lifted on 14 April with health system capacity at 25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1500000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;July 31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ECQ implemented but lifted on 14 April with health system capacity at 50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;15000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;May 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ECQ implemented but lifted on 30 April with health system capacity at 75%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;6800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;May 21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this modelling, &lt;em&gt;peak date&lt;/em&gt; refers to the day with the highest number of cases. The projected maximum number of active confirmed positive cases for the duration of the outbreak is referred to as the “Peak of active confirmed cases”. Meanwhile, health system capacity was defined as a function of (1) testing capacity and (2) health management capacity. Testing capacity refers to the availability of test kits, testing centers with quantitative polymerase chain reaction (qPCR) machines, trained health workers to perform testing, and turnaround time of test results. On the other hand, health management capacity refers to the availability of health facilities, medical devices and health workers to manage the confirmed positive cases so that they are isolated and given proper medical care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Modeling</title>
      <link>/project/topic-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/topic-modelling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
